Guide to the Ruth Asawa Papers M1585
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 19. Calendars, Planners, Notebooks, etc., 1956-2002
  Contains notebooks, day planners, calendars, datebooks, phone logs, address books, mailing lists, and related material. Many notebooks have sketches and doodles by Asawa. Refer to the numbered notebooks in the art series for more of these. Arrangement is chronological, although many notebooks span multiple years or have significant gaps and unused portions, and some are barely used at all. Albert and other family also used the notebooks and logs.
  - address books (Box 179, Folder 1)
  - 1956, 1959, 1964, 1967, 1969 (Box 179, Folder 2)
  - undated early 70s, 1971, 1973 (Box 180, Folder 1)
  - 1974 (Box 180, Folder 2)
  - 1975 (Box 181, Folder 1)
  - 1976 (Box 181, Folder 2)
  - 1976-1977 (Box 182, Folder 1)
  - 1977 (Box 182, Folder 2)
  - 1978 (Box 183, Folder 1)
  - 1979 (Box 184, Folder 1)
  - 1980 (Box 184, Folder 2)
  - 1981 (Box 185, Folder 1)
  - 1982 (Box 185, Folder 2)
  - 1983 (Box 186, Folder 1)
  - 1984 (Box 186, Folder 2)
  - 1985-1986 (Box 187, Folder 1)
    Includes diary from her lupus attack.
  - 1986-1987 (Box 187, Folder 2)
  - 1987-1988 (Box 187, Folder 3)
  - 1989 (Box 188, Folder 1)
  - 1990 (Box 188, Folder 2)
  - 1991 (Box 188, Folder 3)
  - 1992 (Box 189, Folder 1)
  - 1993-1994 (Box 189, Folder 2)
  - 1995 (Box 190, Folder 1)
  - 1996 (Box 190, Folder 2)
  - 1997 (Box 191, Folder 1)
  - 1998-2002 (Box 191, Folder 2)
  - oversize wall calendars [unfoldered] (Box 192)
  - realia (Box 271)
    Buttons, nametags, ID cards, business cards, etc.
- Series 20. Clipping Files, Bibliography
  Newspaper and magazine articles about or mentioning Ruth Asawa. Most are clippings but there are also entire issues. Many feature photographs of Ruth and her art and commissions. Some 1950s magazines feature Ruth and Albert's industrial designs in advertisements, and wire sculptures as props in fashion photographs. Many articles, editorials, and columns are from the San Francisco Chronicle, San Francisco Examiner, Noe Valley Voice, and the Japanese American paper Hokubei Mainichi. An index based on these clipping files, including a listing of books, has been posted in the Stanford Digital Repository as the Ruth Asawa Bibliography: http://purl.stanford.edu/xx128db6087
  - undated, 1948-1964 (Box 243, Folders 1-15)
  - 1965-1972 (Box 244, Folders 1-8)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 245, Folders 1-3)
  - 1975-1981 (Box 246, Folders 1-7)
  - 1982-1986 (Box 247, Folders 1-5)
  - 1987-1993 (Box 248, Folders 1-7)
  - 1994-1996 (Box 249, Folders 1-3)
  - 1997-2002 (Box 250, Folders 1-6)
  - 2003-2007 (Box 251, Folders 1-5)
  - 2008-2014 (Box 252, Folders 1-6)
  - oversize (Box 55, Folders 3)
  - books (Box 265, Box 266)
    Assorted books and publications, the majority of which either refer to Asawa or include her work. Some are inscribed copies. Most are not available in the Stanford library catalog. Refer to the bibliography for a more comprehensive list.
- Series 21. Biographies and Portfolios
  See also grant and fellowship applications.
  - biographies, CV/resumes, etc. (Box 129, Folder 13)
  - unpublished promotional brochure, early 1950s; Conservation treatment: collage was glued back, components were separated and sleeved in mylar. Was Box 132, Folder 3: after treatment item was moved to Flat Box 275. Process was fully documented, refer to JIRA or Conservation records. (Flat-box 275)
    Probable maquette, "never got printed" according to note.
  - bound portfolio [unfoldered], circa 1974 (Box 99)
    "Compiled 1969" but probably from 1974 (Art Commission appointment listed in CV). Many photographs by Paul Hassel, Imogen Cunningham, and Rondal Partridge.
  - portfolio binder, circa 1986 (Box 132, Folder 3)
  - portfolio, circa 1986 (Box 132, Folder 4)
  - portrait for biographies by Allen Nomura, 1986 (Box 132, Folder 7)
  - Alvarado/SOTA scrapbook, 1986 (Box 132, Folder 5)
    "Made by woman from arts collective"
  - bound photocopies of articles, circa 1990 (Box 132, Folder 6)
- Series 22. Juvenalia, School
  See also school drawings, sketches, and scrapbook in Art series.
  Contains notes, artifacts, and other material from Asawa's childhood and schooling in California, Mexico City, Milwaukee, Black Mountain, and San Francisco.
  - 22.1 Norwalk
    - miscellaneous (Box 173, Folder 8)
      Birth certificate; Bellflower Old Timers Reunion flier 1996; Norwalk historical tour brochure; Hargitt House material.
    - Norwalk history books (2) (Box 173, Folder 9)
    - Norwalk School, 1939 (Box 173, Folder 10)
      Staff photograph 10/5/39 (includes Gwendolyn Cowan, Asawa's seventh grade art teacher); program for "White Gypsy" performance 4/27/39 (Ruth played one of the gypsies, her friend Alice played piano); homework assignments, mostly September 1939 (also some schoolwork and drawings from her sister Chiyo).
    - Current Events: The National School Newspaper, 1938-1939 (Flat-box 78, Folder 15)
      Ruth’s name is written on most issues.
    - Excelsior High School, 1939-1996 (Box 173, Folder 11)
      Program for 1939 Christmas concert; Class of 1943 50th reunion material 1993 (including copy of Asawa letter re: internment); Excelsior Life (alumni editions) 1995-1996.
      See the Japanese-American Internment series for more material related to Ruth's education. She continued her studies informally while at Santa Anita and graduated from high school at Rohwer.
    - Excelsior school newspapers, 1939-1941 (Flat-box 55, Folder 12)
      Excelsior Life and Excelsior Spotlight. In Spotlight dated 5/23/1939, Ruth's older sister Lois is listed as a reporter and is mentioned in an article: "Miss Lois Asawa will leave for Japan to enroll in an English Language College in June. Miss Asawa will spend a day at Treasure Island, and hopes to stop over in Honolulu enroute to Japan." In an October 1940 Excelsior Life, Ruth is on the publicity committee for a surrealism-themed dance.
    - Excelsior Reunion [audio], 1993-09-19; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - 22.2 Milwaukee State Teachers College, 1943-1946
    Ruth attended MSTC from September 1943 to June 1946.
    - yearbooks, 1945 (Box 173, Folder 12)
      In the Ivy Annual 1945, Elaine Schmitt is on the art staff and Asawa is listed as "art contributor." Although nothing is attributed, Ruth and Elaine did the faculty caricatures and other incidental illustrations. Ruth is also on C.W.A. [i.e. Civil Works Administration?] Board, and is in their group photograph. There is also a photocopy of a different yearbook with pictures of Ruth and Elaine, as well as her friends Ruth Ewart Muehlmeier and Edith Maletz.
    - bank book (Box 173, Folder 12)
    - drawing of mollusk, 1946-04-12 (Box 173, Folder 12)
      Presumed to be from MSTC.
    - etching from 4th year class, 1945 (Box 173, Folder 12)
    - transcripts (Box 173, Folder 12)
      Includes her 1999 degree award from University of Wisconsin, Milwaukee.
  - 22.3 University of Mexico, Mexico City
    - Mexican History class notes, July-August, 1945 (Box 174, Folder 1)
      Notebook containing many drawings and doodles in addition to class notes.
  - 22.4 Black Mountain College
    See other Black Mountain College series for correspondence and reunion files.
    - application for Spring 1946 [photocopy], 1945-10-02 (Box 174, Folder 2)
    - application for 1946 Summer Art Institute [photocopy] (Box 174, Folder 3)
    - application for Fall 1946 [photocopy], 1946-07 (Box 174, Folder 4)
    - scholarships [originals and copies] (Box 174, Folder 5)
    - grades/evaluations [photocopies], 1946-1949 (Box 174, Folder 6)
    - correspondence - Asawa and college administration [photocopy], 1944-1948 (Box 174, Folder 7)
    - transcript [originals and copies], 1951 (Box 174, Folder 8)
  - 22.5 Black Mountain College class notes
    - Albers (etc.) class notes, undated (Box 174, Folder 9)
    - Albers class notes July-August, 1946 (Box 174, Folder 10)
    - Jean Varda design class notes July-August, 1946 (Box 174, Folder 11)
    - M.C. Richards class notes September-October, 1946 (Box 174, Folder 12)
    - Albers class notes Spring, 1947 (Box 174, Folder 13)
    - Schlesinger music class notes Spring, 1947 (Box 174, Folder 14)
    - Dehn math class notes, 1947-1948 (Box 174, Folder 15)
      Existence and Location of Copies
      161 pages of notes have been scanned.
    - Schlesinger music class notes Spring, 1948 (Box 174, Folder 16)
    - Albers class notes, 1948-1949 (Box 174, Folder 17)
    - Tsui, Albers, Olson etc. class notes, 1949-early 1950s (Box 175, Folder 1)
      notebook labeled "Biology: Dr. Tsui." Includes notes from General Biology Spring 1949, Albers class Spring 1949, an audited Charles Olson class, and later Silkscreening class notes from San Francisco State College.
    - miscellaneous typed classwork (Box 175, Folder 2)
      essay on Paul Klee ("from first year"); senior exam first semester 1946-1947 (photocopy only)
    - Black Mountain College note pages used in the 2006 Asawa Retrospective at de Young Museum
      - "Sonata Sketch" (from music class), [1946] (Box 175, Folder 3)
      - "White Words", [1946] (Box 175, Folder 7)
      - "Meaning of Form, Mirror Drawing" (Albers design class, Summer Institute 1946), 1946-07-03 (Box 175, Folder 8)
      - "F and Meander" [design class, Summer Institute 1946), 1946-07-16 (Box 175, Folder 9)
      - "Greeks - Romans" (design class, Summer Institute 1946), 1946-07-16 (Box 175, Folder 3)
      - "Proportional 1-2-3-4" (design class, Summer Institute 1946), 1946-07-31 (Box 175, Folder 5)
      - "Art is Order" (Albers design class, Summer Institute 1946), 1946-08-07 (Box 175, Folder 10)
      - "E's Loops", [1948] (Box 175, Folder 11)
      - "Figure Background" (Albers design class, Spring 1948), 1948-05-05 (Box 175, Folder 6)
  - 22.6 SF State
    - 1951-1953 (Box 175, Folder 12)
      Includes correspondence concerning credits for her BMC classes, her library card from Spring 1953, an exam essay on the Constitution, dance notation notes, mimeographed folk dance music, and other loose notes and handouts.
- Series 23. Japanese American Internment
  The Asawa family was among the 110,000 West Coast Japanese Americans interned during World War Two. Following Executive Order 9066 Ruth's father Umakichi was arrested in February 1942 by FBI agents and sent to a camp in New Mexico. Two months later, the Asawas were ordered to report to nearby Santa Anita Assembly Center, a hastily converted race track. After several months of waiting, they were transferred to Rohwer War Relocation Center in McGehee, Arkansas. Ruth was in Rohwer for eighteen months, although her mother Haru stayed through 1945.
  At Santa Anita, college students organized classes for younger students so they wouldn't get too behind in their studies. Held in the track's bleachers, they taught Ruth English, Math, Geometry and Art. Her sister, who had attended Long Beach State, taught English. Drawing was taught by former Disney Studio artists Tom Okamoto, Chris Ishii (who created the Lil' Neebo comic while at Santa Anita), Robert Shiroruro Kuwahara, and James Tanaka. Ruth often acknowledged the influence her art teachers had on her, especially Okamoto. "No other 16 year-old Americans were receiving (and still aren't) such training: many hours of instruction and practice with professional artists." Other artists at Santa Anita included Shingo Nishiura, Kinichi Nakanishi, Shinkichi Tojiri, and Hideo Date.
  At Rohwer, Asawa took art classes from Mabel Rose Jamison (later known as Jamie Vogel). They corresponded later, and Jamison sent Ruth her old artwork. Other artists at Rohwer included painter Henry Sugimoto and George Akimoto, who drew Lil Dan’l cartoons for the Rohwer Outpost.
  Ruth graduated from high school in July 1943. With the assistance of the Quaker Japanese American Student Relocation Council, she was told she could continue her study in the Midwest, but not either coast. Since tuition for her first choice, the Art Institute of Chicago, was too expensive, she decided on the more affordable Milwaukee State Teacher's College, where she would train as an art teacher.
  This series contains correspondence with family, friends, and former teachers; ephemera including camp newspapers and the Rohwer High School yearbook (with uncredited drawings by Asawa, who was art editor); notes and interviews; material related to camp reunions and monument efforts; reparation paperwork; reference material for creating the San Jose Internment Memorial, including photographs and photocopied images, articles, newsletters, and magazines such as Nikkei Heritage and the Japanese American National Museum Quarterly. More of this general background information is located with the Memorial files.
  Japanese American evacuation and resettlement; World War, 1939-1945 -- Japanese Americans.
  - 23.1 Santa Anita Assembly Center
    - Santa Anita Pacemaker Vol.1 No.3 April 28, 1942 (Box 172, Folder 4)
      http://library.ci.arcadia.ca.us/SAJAC/04-28-1942.pdf
    - sketches of Santa Anita Racetrack, 1994-04-12 (Box 172, Folder 4)
      Two sides of a Lafayette Manufacturing envelope, drawn as Ruth remembered it. A news program shows her drawing it while sitting in the grandstand.
    - miscellaneous photocopied photographs (Box 172, Folder 4)
  - 23.2 Rohwer Relocation Center
    - Jamison Art Club drawings, 1943 (Box 172, Folder 5)
      Photocopies of art from Vogel’s collection, mostly by Sam Ichiba.
    - Jamison Art Club: list of Asawa art (Box 172, Folder 5)
      List of Ruth’s art from Vogel with notes, probably for 2001 Fresno show.
    - miscellaneous photocopied photographs (Box 172, Folder 5)
    - Selected Photos, Evacuation and Internment of Japanese/Americans from West Coast: Stockton Assembly Center and Santa Anita Assembly Center to Rohwer Relocation Center, McGehee, Arkansas, 1942-1945. [On cover: War Relocation Authority, Rohwer Relocation Center, McGehee, Arkansas 1942-1945] [Los Angeles]: TecCom Productions, 1989 (Box 172, Folder 5)
      not in library catalog
      Published edition of photographs from U.S. Army Signal Corp., Associated Press and others.
    - George Akimoto, "Lil' Dan'l: One Year in a Relocation Center", 1989 (Box 172, Folder 5)
      1989 reproduction (with new typeset) of Akimoto's 1944 comic book "Lil' Dan'l: One Year in a Relocation Center," with enclosed Hokubei Mainichi article. Akimoto, who lives in Stockton, had the reproduction made himself. His art was also featured in the Rohwer Outpost.
      Akimoto, George
    - Rohwer Center High School Class of 1943 Commencement program [photocopy], 1943-07 (Box 172, Folder 5)
      With Ruth, George and Victor Asawa.
    - research photos and negatives (Box 172, Folder 5)
      Most are derived from print sources.
    - Rohwer Outpost letterhead stationery (Box 172, Folder 6)
      Asawa was editor for one issue of the camp newspaper.
    - Leisure Time Program Groups, Summer, 1943 (Box 172, Folder 6)
    - Delta Round-Up yearbook Spring, 1943 (Box 172, Folders 7-8)
      Two bound copies, one of which was Asawa's and is heavily inscribed, two unbound partial copies with no inset photographs (probably proofs), and one photocopy. Ruth, who was the uncredited art director for the yearbook, is probably the artist behind several caricatures and other illustrations.
    - Rohwer Restoration Project, 1994-02-02 (Box 172, Folder 9)
      Letter from project coordinator George Sakaguchi with photographs of monuments at Jerome and Rohwer.
    - Laurie: Rohwer Today (Box 172, Folder 10)
      Photographs of Rohwer monuments and gravestones (probably by Addie Lanier).
    - Rohwer High School reunion program, 1980-05 (Box 173, Folder 1)
      Reunion was in Stockton, California. Program includes reproduced letters from Vogel/Jamison and Betty Hunter, whose father was Dr. Hunter, who had assisted with monument upkeep.
    - Rohwer Outpost [reunion edition] No.1-3, 5-8, 1989-1990 (Box 173, Folder 2)
      published by the First Rohwer Reunion Committee.
    - First Rohwer Reunion, 1990 (Box 173, Folder 3)
      This reunion took place July 20-21, 1990 in Los Angeles. File contains a "mini-yearbook," booklet and program, as well as photographs, slides, and negatives. The yearbook features photos of Ruth, Addie and other Asawa family members, including Chiyo Asawa Knewbow, George and Florence Asawa Hamamoto, George and Sako Asawa, George and Masako Asawa, Janet Asawa Davis, Lois Asawa Shishido, Joe and Mary Asawa Oye, and Stella Asawa Yano.
    - Rohwer Reunion III, 2001-10 (Box 173, Folder 4)
    - notes about camp (Box 173, Folder 5)
      Includes speech draft, 1998 student interview, document recounting Asawa family activity during the war.
    - unidentified student art [not by Asawa] (Flat-box 78, Folder 13)
      Most or all from Rohwer according to attached notes.
  - 23.3 miscellaneous (Box 173, Folder 7)
    American Friends Service Committee policy handbook; address label from father to Milwaukee 8/7/44; Lois Asawa's menu from MS Tatuta Maru 10/29/1941 (with sketches presumably by her).
  - 23.4 conferences, exhibitions, other events, 1976-2010 (Box 171, Folder 3)
  - 23.5 Day of Remembrance Curriculum Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 171, Folder 5)
  - 23.6 correspondence
    - undated, 1975-1990 (Box 172, Folder 1)
    - 1991-1994 (Box 172, Folder 2)
    - 1995-2013 (Box 172, Folder 3)
  - 23.7 A/V
    - Ruth Asawa Interview on Japanese American Internment Camps During World War II. Granby High School [Norfolk, Virginia] 9th Grade World History, History Day Project [audio], 1998-03-16; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 79, Folder 11)
      High school students Robin Veracruz, Lauren Leaptrot, and Stephanie Owens interview Ruth Asawa about her internment experience. See transcripts. The students sent Ruth their interview form with their notes along with a copy of the tape.
    - NBC Reports "Guilty By Reason of Race" [video], 1972-09-19; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 43, Folder 3)
      NBC documentary re: Japanese-American Internment. NATIONAL BROADCASTING SERVICE; FILMS INCORPORATED/PMI; 1972. 18:34 Santa Anita
    - The New Americans #110. Starting Over: Japanese Americans After The War. B. Somerville, KCSM, 1996; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 49, Folder 8)
      Produced and directed by Dianne Fukami, Copyright 1996 San Mateo County Community College District.
    - A Personal Matter: Gordon Hirabayashi Vs. The United States. Crosscurrent Media, 1992; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 49, Folder 9)
      Not digitized. Copyright 1992, The Constitution Project. 2011 DVD Distributed by Center for Asian American Media
  - 23.8 reparations paperwork, 1988-1991 (Box 173, Folder 6)
    Includes photocopy of Asawa's reparation check from the United States government.
  - 23.9 reference material, publications
    - Nikkei Heritage (NJAHS), 1991-1996 (Box 170, Folder 1)
    - National Council for Japanese American Redress newsletter, 1987-1989 (Box 170, Folder 2)
    - Japanese American National Museum Quarterly, 1989-1996 (Box 170, Folder 3)
    - articles, 1969-1988 (Box 170, Folder 5)
    - articles, 1989-1991 (Box 170, Folder 6)
    - articles, 1992 (Box 170, Folder 7)
    - articles, 1993-1997 (Box 171, Folder 1)
    - articles, 1998-2012 (Box 171, Folder 2)
    - other periodicals (Box 170, Folder 4)
      NJAHS Focus, JANL Bulletin, Nikkei Family, Japanese Cultural and Community Center of Northern California newsletter.
    - other publications (Box 169, Folder 6)
      brochures, pamphlets, three different photocopies of conspiracy tract "War Lords of Washington," sent by Asawa's cousin Stella.
    - unpublished writing (Box 171, Folder 4)
    - calendars, 1989-1996 (Box 169, Folder 7)
      From the National Japanese American Historical Society and Japanese American National Museum.
- Series 24. Family
  Files concerning the Asawa and and Lanier families. Much more can be found in other series, especially Aiko Cuneo and Paul Lanier, both of whom taught art and worked on commissions.
  - Albert Lanier (Box 175, Folder 13)
    letterhead from architecture firm; notebooks with phone messages and SOTA-related notes 1976, 1996-1999; real estate ad for home he designed; Ruth and Albert 40th Anniversary invitation; memorial program with drawings by Asawa; obituaries from Noe Valley Voice and SF Chronicle; condolence from Board of Supervisors, etc.
  - Asawas (Box 175, Folder 14)
    Asawa family documentation; card from sister Janet, correspondence with first cousin Stella Yano (more elsewhere); color copies of 1976 photographs of family gathering in Idaho, etc.
  - Ruth with Albert's Family in Georgia [photographs], 1949 (Box 175, Folder 15)
    Photographs, both original and copies, of Ruth in Georgia with Laurie Pearson, Ann and Peggy.
  - miscellaneous (Box 175, Folder 16)
    Family cards, letters, photographs, notebook (with Japanese writing lessons, children’s art, some Ruth sketches), etc.
  - Paul Lanier (Box 175, Folder 17)
    mostly exhibition announcements for his pottery.
  - Brian Asawa (Box 175, Folder 18)
    Brian, a professional singer, is Ruth's nephew. Contains a postcard, fliers, promotional material, and articles. See also Secondary Uses file.
  - lupus get well soon cards (Box 175, Folder 19)
  - drawing of eyes - Lanier children (Box 197, Folder 5)
- Series 25. Audiovisual Media and Photographs
  Most media and photographs have been listed with their relevant subject files. This series contains interviews and profiles of Asawa, as well as material about her house, studio and garden.
  - 25.1 interviews, news profiles, etc.
    - Asawa/Goldstine at de Young Museum, 1974-06-10; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 41, Folder 2)
      Panel of Elsa Cameron, Stephen Goldstine, Ruth Asawa, Richard Pron [?], Joan Abramson. Asawa interviewed re: Alvarado, art education, her life (farming, internment, BMC)
    - Ruth Asawa and Clark Mitze Interviews w/Christian Lauritzen courtesy KORV Radio, 1976; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 40, Folder 16)
      Oroville, CA radio interview, "Viewpoint" program. Asawa producing puppet show at Chinese Temple in area, had helped produce wooden Ishi statue, 1976; [12:19] Mitze director of California State Council on the Arts.
    - Of Forms and Growth. Robert Snyder, 1978; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Available through Stanford Libraries' Media and Microtext department: http://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/6779925
      Documentary on Ruth Asawa.
    - Ruth, 1980s; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 41, Folder 1)
      Side A: unidentified live and recorded Japanese music. solo reed instrument; Japanese koto; reed and drums; koto (from recording?); flute. Side B: audio from program ("AM Weekend" probably KGO, Ray Taliaferro), Asawa interviewed at School Works Unlimited store at Emporium (recorded twice); Barbara Streisand "Funny Girl" recordings.
    - Asawa #1, #2. Interview By Wendy Garfield, 1980-07-07; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Ruth Asawa, 1980-07-09; 2 audiocassette(s) (Box 41, Folder 4)
      Probably continuation of Garfield interview. Garfield (?), Asawa discussion, others present (Addie? teachers) re: Alvarado, store at Emporium, etc. Tape 2 Side B: [20:23] woman singing with guitar, 2 songs.
    - Horizons, KGO-TV with Ruth Ajana [Asawa]. From BayScene, 1982-07-17; 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 43, Folder 5)
      "The World of Ruth Asawa" profile, Bayscene program
    - Ruth Asawa Interview AE [Artists Equity] - Carolyn Marks and Chiori Santiago, 1985-02; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 41, Folder 5)
      Asawa interviewed by Marks (Berkeley artist) and Santiago (journalist, wrote several articles about Ruth) re: Artists Equity, etc. poss. for Metier magazine
    - Ruth Asawa on Internment, 1990; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 41, Folder 7)